<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Chatwoot blog's RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Chatwoot is an open-source customer engagement platform that helps companies engage their customers on their website, Facebook page, Twitter, Whatsapp, SMS, email, etc. Chatwoot is an open-source alternative to Intercom, Zendesk, Salesforce Service Cloud etc. Connect your customer conversation channels and converse with your customers from a single place.]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 14:15:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Pre chat form + Automations = 🚀]]></title><description><![CDATA[You can now get all the information you need about a contact before they even start a conversation with you. By using pre-chat forms along with automation, you'll save time and increase productivity. ✨]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/pre-chat-form-automations</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/pre-chat-form-automations</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 11:09:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When you already have context on the problem you&apos;re dealing with, you can solve it quicker and better. Live chat support agents understand this very well. But if you are forced to ask the same questions again and again — May I please have your registered email address?, how can I help you today? let me transfer your chat to the relevant team. — the inefficiency increases for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The good news: you can avoid these questions by collecting information about your customers as soon as they enter your live chat window, with the help of our pre-chat forms. You can also set up specific rules to determine who to assign these conversations to, what labels to add, or what else to do with such conversations. This creates a suitable workflow for your team, sparing them a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works. ⬇️&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-i-collect-user-info-with-pre-chat-forms&quot;&gt;Step I. Collect user info with pre-chat forms&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A pre-chat form is something your visitors fill out before entering into a live chat with you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of how it looks:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2022/05/ezgif-2-9deec18cd4.gif&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;964&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-are-pre-chat-forms-helpful&quot;&gt;Why are pre-chat forms helpful?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every business and industry can make use of pre-chat forms. However, there are certain common benefits of this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A better first point of contact for the customers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More meaningful interaction between the customer and agent&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better cross-team collaboration and efficient customer service process&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Decreased conversation resolution time&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reduced agent workload&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More satisfied customers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Happier customer support agents 😁&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recommended&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chatwoot.com/docs/user-guide/features/pre-chat-form&quot;&gt;Step-by-step guide to enabling pre-chat forms in Chatwoot.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-ii-add-automation-rules-for-simpler-workflows&quot;&gt;Step II. Add Automation Rules for simpler workflows&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After you&apos;ve received information through your pre-chat form, you can automatically assign customers to specific teams, trigger specific responses, add labels, mute conversations and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just add Automation rules from the &lt;em&gt;Settings&lt;/em&gt; tab on your Chatwoot dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is an example where a conversation is automatically assigned to the France Sales team whenever a conversation is created and the Browser language is detected as French:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2022/05/live-chat-automation.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1244&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w600/2022/05/live-chat-automation.jpeg 600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1000/2022/05/live-chat-automation.jpeg 1000w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1600/2022/05/live-chat-automation.jpeg 1600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w2400/2022/05/live-chat-automation.jpeg 2400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chatwoot.com/docs/user-guide/features/automations&quot;&gt;Here is a detailed guide on using Automations in Chatwoot.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;power-play-with-automations&quot;&gt;Power Play with Automations&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pre-chat forms together with Automation rules can do wonders for your Customer Support workflows. You can set up multiple rules to delight your users as well as save your team’s time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you run an e-commerce store. You can enable a pre-chat form for your live chat widget with fields like:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Name [&lt;em&gt;text type&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Email ID [&lt;em&gt;email type&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Type of issue [&lt;em&gt;list to choose from: tracking, payment, cancellation, etc&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Issue description [&lt;em&gt;message]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To club with, you can make an Automation Rule. So, whenever a conversation is created &lt;em&gt;plus&lt;/em&gt; a message containing “payment” is incoming, it would be assigned to the finance team and a label saying “payment_issue” would be added. You can add another rule that would trigger a message saying “Someone will be with you shortly.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, whenever agents open the chat, they’ll have all the relevant information at their fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How are you going to use the Automations? Let us know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Related Read: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/the-complete-guide-to-building-your-customer-experience-strategy-in-2022/&quot;&gt;The complete guide to building your customer experience strategy in 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The complete guide to building your customer experience strategy in 2022]]></title><description><![CDATA[Customer experience is what shall differentiate your brand from others. It's here to stay and is going to become an important factor in determining key business performance indicators like retention and sales. Here are all of the actions you should take to create an effective CX strategy in 2022.]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/the-complete-guide-to-building-your-customer-experience-strategy-in-2022</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/the-complete-guide-to-building-your-customer-experience-strategy-in-2022</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 14:23:40 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Businesses exist to make lives better for the people they serve. If you’re away from your customers, you’re away from the problems they’re facing and away from your mission. The simplest answer to this is? Just be present for them every step of the way – create a 360-degree customer experience that basically tells your customers you’re here for them. Customer experience or CX defines how they interact with your business and how satisfied they are with that experience. That’s it, that’s the only trick you need to know to succeed! &lt;em&gt;Okay, maybe not.&lt;/em&gt; But, what next? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having a customers communication management system in place becomes very important. In simpler words, just find a way that works best for your team to be available to talk to your customers whenever required. And if you keep customer experience trends in mind as you do so, you&apos;ll be way ahead of the game. Don&apos;t worry – we&apos;ve done the groundwork for you. So, what are the customer experience trends to look out for in 2022, what are the challenges to expect, and what solutions and tools do you have at your disposal? Let’s see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2022/04/giphy.gif&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;226&quot; height=&quot;309&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;customer-experience-cx-trends-in-2022&quot;&gt;Customer experience (CX) trends in 2022&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rapid digitization&lt;/strong&gt;: Until 2020, an online presence was an important thing to have. In the past couple of years, digital channels have increasingly become a first-hand traffic source, i.e. people come to you via online routes. The onset of COVID-19 gave everyone more time to spend in front of their screens. The Web has taken over markets, businesses, and customers faster than experts ever thought it would. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/strategy-and-corporate-finance/our-insights/how-covid-19-has-pushed-companies-over-the-technology-tipping-point-and-transformed-business-forever&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; by MicKinsey suggests that 80% of businesses&apos; customer interactions are now digital in nature – a metric that was expected about 3 years from now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A shift from personalization to hyper-personalization&lt;/strong&gt;: Businesses are gathering user data from various channels to create customized customer experiences to deliver tailored products, services, and information. Support agents get user data instantly, which helps them help users through the journey in a way that suits them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer to customer&lt;/strong&gt;: A C2C trend is on the rise where people come together through communities like forums and groups to trade products, services, or information. Platforms help create a space for customers and encourage growth for everyone. That&apos;s why it pays to learn about them even if you’re not running a platform business.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customers are more aware&lt;/strong&gt;: Customers are becoming increasingly aware of and concerned by the impact of their purchase choices. If a cause demands it, they would choose an alternative product.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customers care about the personality of your business&lt;/strong&gt;: Brands have started making a connection with their customers. People buy for the story, the cause, the ‘why’ and ‘how’ behind the product now. Having a unique voice for your brand is going to matter even more in the coming years. This is possible by building a character for your brand and genuinely making relationships with your existing and potential customers and community.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An omnichannel presence&lt;/strong&gt;: Customers have grown accustomed to seeing businesses have a consistent presence across all online platforms. Having this consistency has become a standard customers expectation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customers care about the experience being provided&lt;/strong&gt;: The customer journey that a brand provides has become a key differentiator. Everything you do from the time a customer sees your brand until and after they make purchase matters. Brands must think about ways to make customer journeys thoughtful and memorable.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More accessible customer service: &lt;/strong&gt;Brands have made customer service more accessible for customers through a mobile-first approach. They are constantly present to chat on familiar apps like WhatsApp, Facebook, and more.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI is empowering businesses while providing the human touch to customers&lt;/strong&gt;: Bots have become as good as agents. They not only provide helpful, real-time customer service but also access user data to provide personalized answers. And we’ve not even harnessed its full power yet. Read more about it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cmswire.com/customer-experience/4-ways-that-ai-is-improving-the-customer-experience/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long story short&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Customer experience is what shall differentiate your brand from others. It’s here to stay and is going to become an important factor in determining key business performance indicators like retention and sales.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But wait – let&apos;s first address what you need to be thinking about when creating your CX strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-important-things-to-consider&quot;&gt;Some important things to consider&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy compliance&lt;/strong&gt;: When you’re building a system to interact with your customers, you’ll be responsible for the user data that you collect. No matter where you’re registered in the world, you’ll need to comply with the data privacy laws of the country where your users are. Such regulations require organizations to implement reasonable data protection measures like end-to-end encryption, guidelines for data breaches, etc. You can choose to collect this data yourself or through a third-party tool. However, do keep in mind that you will always be considered accountable for its ethical usage. Hold on to that thought as it will be of utmost importance as we proceed with this article. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building an omnichannel presence&lt;/strong&gt;: People are spoilt with options. This also means you want to give them the choice of which platform they want to interact with your business depending on the nature of the problem. This flexibility is not a luxury but an expectation now. The major issue: The omnichannel approach has created a burdensome situation for customer service reps. They switch between multiple screens thousands of times a day. So look for a solution that can centralize all of your communications. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Befriend the bots&lt;/strong&gt;: Do yourself a favour and get a chatbot. Name her something that people are fascinated with. Spend some time understanding how it can integrate into your existing workflow. Now, wait and watch as it generates qualified leads for you, while building a personality for your business (this is an important emerging CX trend, remember?). &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opensource vs Cloud: &lt;/strong&gt;When building your customer engagement stack, you’ll come across a lot of open source and cloud options. Here are the things to consider when making a choice –&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: html--&gt;&lt;table style=&quot;border:none;border-collapse:collapse;table-layout:fixed;width:auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;colgroup&gt; &lt;col width=&quot;149&quot;&gt; &lt;col width=&quot;235&quot;&gt; &lt;col width=&quot;235&quot;&gt; &lt;/colgroup&gt; &lt;tbody&gt; &lt;tr style=&quot;height:0pt&quot;&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:700;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Open source software&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:700;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Cloud tooling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;height:0pt&quot;&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;What does this even mean?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;An open source software basically has its source code available to the public for modification and usage best suited to their use case.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;You subscribe to a SAAS (software as a service) managed by a brand on the web by paying recurring fees.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;height:0pt&quot;&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Rapid deployment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;You can immediately release your own versions of the software without much reluctance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;You’ll be dependent on the brand for the next version of the product which wouldn’t be hyper-personalized for your use case.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;height:0pt&quot;&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Community collaboration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;There are multiple ways of solving a problem or improving upon software. The open source community is always passionate about contributing to your project and sharing ideas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;At most, you can connect with people through forums to exchange ideas.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;height:0pt&quot;&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Privacy regulations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;You’ll be the owner of your user data. As long as you’re using it in an ethical way and not violating any regulations, you’ll be good to go.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Using a third-party app makes them the data processor for you. However, you’re responsible for your customers’ privacy. You’ll need to have a hard check on whether the tool you’re using is GDPR compliant or not.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;height:0pt&quot;&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Software updates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;You update your software according to your own convenience and use case.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;The brand constantly updates the web application keeping the larger audience in mind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;height:0pt&quot;&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Major costs involved&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;You need to invest in IT personnel. This cost can be minimized too if the brand managing the open source project has proper documentation in place.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Subscription fees, managing personnel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;height:0pt&quot;&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Technical know-how&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;A good technical knowledge is required. You will need to invest in technical personnel to maintain this.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;These tools are designed to be user-friendly and usually do not require much technical context to effectively use them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;height:0pt&quot;&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Bugfixes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;You’re responsible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;The brand is responsible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr style=&quot;height:0pt&quot;&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;A support system is there but its structure varies from brand to brand.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;border-left:solid #000000 1pt;border-right:solid #000000 1pt;border-bottom:solid #000000 1pt;border-top:solid #000000 1pt;vertical-align:top;padding:5pt 5pt 5pt 5pt;overflow:hidden;overflow-wrap:break-word;&quot;&gt; &lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.2;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:11pt;font-family:Arial;color:#000000;background-color:transparent;font-weight:400;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;text-decoration:none;vertical-align:baseline;white-space:pre;white-space:pre-wrap;&quot;&gt;Constant support is available.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-end: html--&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, you know which are the points to consider when building your tooling stack. Save this up for reference and go with a solution that best suits your needs!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-complete-picture&quot;&gt;The complete picture&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Customer experience should be a vital part of your business framework. To make this happen, you need a strong customer-relationship-management (CRM) system, automated workflows wherever possible, and an app stack that is connected and flexible. What’s even more important is having a mutual CRM strategy across your marketing, sales, and support teams. This will make for a frictionless sales funnel and will help your marketing efforts be more informed about your customers&apos; needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The benefits of this are unmatched –&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Once you’re better aware of the problems your users are facing, the kind of mindset they have, and the things they care about, you can drive your marketing efforts accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You’ll get an invaluable insight into your users’ preferences and pressing concerns. This will help you stay ahead of the competition.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The invaluable insights into your customers’ mindset enable the product and sales teams to improve the user journey.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;instant-help-and-support-through-live-chat&quot;&gt;Instant help and support through live chat&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;By now we know that we want to build or improve the way we communicate with our customers. We also saw the importance of giving instant resources to customers (existing and potential) whenever they’re looking for information. The best way to go about this is to integrate the option of live chat into your customer service strategy. Why so? Here are some quick points to consider:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;According to all the modern customer satisfaction surveys conducted, live chat stays on top of the list, after phone support and help center articles. This means that people not only care about instant help, but also about the privilege of talking through their issues in real-time, sharing links, and saving up information. You can check out this 50 Useful Live Chat Stats and Trends &lt;a href=&quot;https://thrivemyway.com/live-chat-stats/#:~:text=a%20chat%20transcript.-,Future%20of%20Live%20Chat%20Stats,industries%20for%20live%20chat%20adoption.&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Both old and new customers are likely to abandon their purchase if the information is not readily available. This is where live chat where a human/bot is constantly available becomes extremely vital. When customers or clients need help completing a task or transaction, they appreciate being able to discuss their options with someone right away.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your users’ support history and key information are available with you at all times if you use a good live chat tool. The thing is that even customers know and expect this. So they see value in interacting with you through app windows and not having to repeat their information.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can maintain a full history of the chats your agents have had through the live chat software you’re using. You can use labels and notes to collaborate with your teammates and be on the same page about a user’s current status no matter who takes the chat next.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Regardless of all the benefits and statistics supporting live chat, the truth remains that people expect this option from brands now. That means if you can’t give it to them, the one who is giving it might steal away your customers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-we-building-an-all-in-one-solution-at-chatwoot&quot;&gt;How are we building an all-in-one solution at Chatwoot?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are several awesome web tools that will help you set up and manage your communication with your customers easily. However, Chatwoot came into being when its creators felt like there was no go-to one-stop solution for all the challenges that support teams face on a regular basis. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s an overview of what we’ve been building:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-host it or use it on the cloud&lt;/strong&gt;: We built Chatwoot, a 360-degree communications management dashboard. We built the MVP and open sourced it on Github so that others could self-host the software and build their own custom version. Our Cloud Subscription allows you to save time and focus on your most important tasks. Our Enterprise Edition integrates Chatwoot into your existing workflow.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy-compliant&lt;/strong&gt;: Self-hosting Chatwoot makes you the sole owner of your user data and keeps you away from the increasing privacy concerns of the world. We also follow strict GDPR regulations for the SAAS version. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Omnichannel&lt;/strong&gt;: Chatwoot supports live-chat widget, Facebook pages, Twitter profiles, WhatsApp, Email, etc., as channels. If you want to build a custom channel, you can create it using the API channel.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instant user data availability&lt;/strong&gt;: You can view and filter all the relevant data for your customers on the &lt;em&gt;Contacts tab &lt;/em&gt;or alongside your chat&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;You can also add custom attributes and share this data across teams for facilitating better decision-making.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations and webhooks&lt;/strong&gt;: Chatwoot connects with your favourite apps like Slack and WordPress. You can even connect with Dialogflow and Rasa to build a chatbot.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can even customize your chat widget, collaborate with your team, add automation rules, and use the mobile app version to stay connected with your customers on the go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s what the dashboard looks like:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2022/04/dashboard-Chatwoot.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1250&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w600/2022/04/dashboard-Chatwoot.png 600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1000/2022/04/dashboard-Chatwoot.png 1000w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1600/2022/04/dashboard-Chatwoot.png 1600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2022/04/dashboard-Chatwoot.png 2000w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Give it a try! If you have any questions or feedback, join the community on &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/invite/cJXdrwS&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;summing-up&quot;&gt;Summing up&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;More and more customers expect businesses to be available and responsive online. Having a communications system in place with your customers and prospects shall help you build a human connection, understand them better, and serve them faster. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We&apos;d love to hear about how you&apos;re using new customer experience trends to engage with customers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chatwootapp&quot;&gt;Tweet at us&lt;/a&gt; and let us know.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building a community around a product]]></title><description><![CDATA[Building a community around a product is hard. It takes a good amount of effort to create an active group of enthusiastic people about what you are building. Being open source simplifies the process. However, continuing the progress without burnout is a balance. ]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/building-a-community-around-a-product</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/building-a-community-around-a-product</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 03:45:19 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Building a community around a product is hard. It takes a good amount of effort to create a group of people enthusiastic about what you are building. Being opensource simplifies the process. However, continuing the progress without burnout is a balance. Here are some of the learning from building a community around &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chatwootapp&quot;&gt;@chatwootapp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;etiquette&quot;&gt;Etiquette&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ground rules:&lt;/strong&gt; Every product community should have some ground rules. It keeps the conversation sane. Adopting a code of conduct would help you when some abusive actors are in the group—whether or not to kick the person would be more straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We adopted Contributor Covenant 4.0 for our contributors/community. You can read more about it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/code-of-conduct/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be polite and build a genuine interest in people&apos;s problems:&lt;/strong&gt; When people ask questions, provide feedback, or make changes, it is essential to give feedback as they are making an effort to fit the product in their use cases. They might be using it from a different angle that you have not thought of before. Having an open mind on product usage would help uncover hidden secrets. If you spend time understanding the pain and resonate with the situation, people would appreciate it, bringing positive energy to the group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work in threads:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are using Slack / Discord, try to work on threads. Direct replies are often chaotic. If not, you would spend most of the time finding the needle in the haystack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use public channels only: &lt;/strong&gt;We use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/chatwoot&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/cJXdrwS&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; at Chatwoot. Github is less intrusive as it doesn&apos;t allow you to send a personal message to a person, and it works asynchronously. For Discord, it is not the case. As it is chat-based, people expect to get immediate responses. I would suggest discouraging the people on DMs. Instead, ask them to move to a public channel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-the-time-and-the-community&quot;&gt;Managing the time and the community&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule time to work with the community:&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of spending all day active in the community, try spending dedicated time with the community. This will give you focused time for community engagement and an uninterrupted time for the rest of your work. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You don&apos;t have to be available every hour you are working. If your &quot;zone&quot; happens to be in the morning, you can disable the notifications in the morning and spend 1-2 hours every evening to make sure that you didn&apos;t miss anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your goal is not to solve the problem immediately:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are trying to solve a problem immediately, you might get lost in that, and the work you have been doing before will become pending. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As humans, this situation would put you in a bad spot where you regret the time spent and would tend to overwork. The easiest way to solve this is to make sure that you have captured the problem in a Github[bug tracker] issue and leave the problem for a later time. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If something takes more than 10 minutes of your time, then it is always better to start with an issue, collect your thoughts and record it properly. Send the issue link to the community member to acknowledge that their voice is heard. Even if the problem has a very small fix, I would suggest creating the issues first instead of fixing them, as the cost of a context switch might not be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn to say no: &lt;/strong&gt;If you are an open-source project, you might see a lot of requests to help in custom work which might not even help the actual project. Sometimes people might push your boundaries. It is essential to understand that you are not obliged to work on it unless you wish to and it is perfectly fine to say no.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;growing-the-community&quot;&gt;Growing the community&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build promoters inside the community&lt;/strong&gt;: It doesn&apos;t have to be you or your team who always reply to a question—building a group of people who is just as passionate as you would help in the long term. Help people to be product experts. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reward the community members:&lt;/strong&gt; Build a reward structure for the users&apos; effort into the community. This doesn&apos;t need to be monetary or goodies. You can start with assigning specific badges for active users. Gamification can bring exponential outcomes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A good example for this is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://productexperts.withgoogle.com/how-it-works&quot;&gt;Google Product Experts&lt;/a&gt; program encouraging people to answer user questions in the Google Help Communities&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-19-at-7.54.29-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;1234&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-19-at-7.54.29-PM.png 600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-19-at-7.54.29-PM.png 1000w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-19-at-7.54.29-PM.png 1600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-19-at-7.54.29-PM.png 2152w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Experts categorize their community contributors to Bronze, Silver, Gold, Platinum &amp;amp; Diamond incentivizing the effort from the members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A community can be a powerful weapon in building and growing your product. Hope these learning help you in building yours. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Checkout our community at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/chatwoot&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/cJXdrwS&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any thoughts or suggestions, please comment below or feel free to reach out to me.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2.0 release, EE Edition, et al.]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello everyone,

Today we are announcing 2.0 - a new major version of Chatwoot that improves the
product stability, adds new features and productivity enhancements, and a
complete design overhaul. This release also marks our first Enterprise edition
offering. 

2.0 release
2.0 version ships with an updated dashboard that is completely redesigned for a
better user experience. This update ships with many new features, including more
communication channels, productivity enhancements, better convers]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/2-0-release-ee-edition-et-al</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/2-0-release-ee-edition-et-al</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 07:12:31 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today we are announcing 2.0 - a new major version of Chatwoot that improves the product stability, adds new features and productivity enhancements, and a complete design overhaul. This release also marks our first Enterprise edition offering. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;20-release&quot;&gt;2.0 release&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;2.0 version ships with an updated dashboard that is completely redesigned for a better user experience. This update ships with many new features, including more communication channels, productivity enhancements, better conversations visibility, re-engagement options, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 id=&quot;%F0%9F%92%AC-communicate-with-your-customers-irrespective-of-the-medium&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;💬 Communicate with your customers irrespective of the medium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chatwoot provides a unified inbox of conversations. You don&apos;t have to switch between tools to connect with your customers. We support the following communication channels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Website Live-chat&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Facebook&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Instagram&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;WhatsApp&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;SMS&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Telegram&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Line&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;API channel for custom needs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chatwoot helps you to communicate within your organization. For example, you can create a group of employees as teams and assign the ownership of a conversation to a team. To communicate internally, you can now use private notes and @mentions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🤩 Engage the customers based on their profile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With our updated CRM, you can now synchronize your customer information by adding our SDK to your website/app. In addition, you can define custom attributes for the customers based on your requirements, tag them, and filter them on their characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also introduced a new feature for adding notes which helps you to log your calls/emails/conversations you had with your customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚡️ Improve your team&apos;s productivity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can now use Command bar for quick access to all the commands you use in Chatwoot and use keyboard shortcuts for increased productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;enterprise-edition-ee&quot;&gt;Enterprise Edition (EE)&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, we are excited to announce our enterprise edition software. For all future releases, you will see two versions of Chatwoot, Community Edition and Enterprise Edition (EE).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will include the features such as customisable dashboards, SLA Management, Agent scheduling software, IP blocklisting etc., suited for large organizations in the Enterprise Edition software. In contrast, Small and medium businesses would continue to use the Community edition. We are making the license update in the repository to include a dual licensing option. All the code available before this change and the future community edition updates would continue to be in the MIT license, and we promise that we will not move any feature that was shipped in CE to EE. All the contents of the folder &lt;code&gt;/enterprise&lt;/code&gt; is copyrighted, and you would need to purchase a license or signup at our Cloud offering to use these features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hope that making our EE Edition code source available adds transparency to our business and the product. We are excited to hear your thoughts and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;contributor-hall-of-fame&quot;&gt;Contributor Hall of Fame&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The community has been core to our success so far. It is rewarding to see people from different countries and cultures come together for a common goal. Our product supports more than 30 languages right now, and all of it was contributed by the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We want to honor and extend our gratitude to the people who have put the effort in helping us to make this software better every day. We are excited to announce the contributor&apos;s hall of fame. This website would show all the contributors who have contributed to Chatwoot. Be it a code change, a doc update, or a language contribution. We value every contribution you have made.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We are really excited to bring this to you all. Let us know your thoughts and feedback !&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chatwoot - September Update]]></title><description><![CDATA[I'm excited to share the updates for the last month. We were trending on the Github trending list in September.

🔥 New Channels - Line & Telegram
Now you can communicate with your customers from Line & Telegram on Chatwoot.]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/chatwoot-september-update</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/chatwoot-september-update</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 06:50:24 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m excited to share the updates for the last month. We were trending on the Github trending list in September.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;%F0%9F%94%A5-new-channelsline-telegram&quot;&gt;🔥 New Channels - Line &amp;amp; Telegram&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now you can communicate with your customers from Line &amp;amp; Telegram on Chatwoot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2021/10/Group.jpg&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;1322&quot; height=&quot;970&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/10/Group.jpg 600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/10/Group.jpg 1000w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2021/10/Group.jpg 1322w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;%F0%9F%94%8B-digitalocean-one-click-deploys&quot;&gt;🔋 DigitalOcean one-click deploys&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now have our One-click app on DigitalOcean marketplace. Checkout Chatwoot one-click installer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.digitalocean.com/apps/chatwoot&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;https://marketplace.digitalocean.com/apps/chatwoot&lt;/a&gt; and deploy Chatwoot easily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;%F0%9F%A7%91%E2%80%8D%F0%9F%92%BB-hacktoberfest&quot;&gt;🧑‍💻 Hacktoberfest&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are participating in Hacktoberfest 2021. For those who don&apos;t know about Hacktoberfest, it is an annual event conducted by DigitalOcean to promote open-source contributions and build awareness about open-source communities. Look at the guidelines on how to participate in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/hacktoberfest-2021-at-chatwoot&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;%F0%9F%91%A5-community&quot;&gt;👥 Community&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our friends at &lt;a href=&quot;https://beeper.com&quot;&gt;BeeperHQ&lt;/a&gt; created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/beeper/chatwoot&quot;&gt;Matrix Beeper bot&lt;/a&gt; that logs in as a help user in Matrix and mirrors all messages sent from Matrix into Chatwoot and allows Chatwoot agents to respond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;%F0%9F%A4%98-get-started&quot;&gt;🤘 Get started&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Start using Chatwoot on Cloud: &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.chatwoot.com&quot;&gt;https://app.chatwoot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Spin up a Self-hosted instance: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chatwoot.com/docs/self-hosted&quot;&gt;https://www.chatwoot.com/docs/self-hosted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make sure to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/chatwoot&quot;&gt;star us on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Follow us &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chatwootapp&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/chatwoot&quot;&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Become a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/chatwoot&quot;&gt;sponsor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hacktoberfest 2021 at Chatwoot]]></title><description><![CDATA[We are happy to announce that we are participating in Hacktoberfest 2021. For those who don't know about Hacktoberfest, it is an annual event conducted by DigitalOcean to promote open-source contributions and build awareness about open-source communities. ]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/hacktoberfest-2021-at-chatwoot</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/hacktoberfest-2021-at-chatwoot</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 08:28:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that we are participating in Hacktoberfest 2021. For those who don&apos;t know about Hacktoberfest, it is an annual event conducted by DigitalOcean to promote open-source contributions and build awareness about open-source communities. This year it is supported by an array of great companies, as shown below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-01-at-1.50.37-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;175&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-01-at-1.50.37-PM.png 600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-01-at-1.50.37-PM.png 1000w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1600/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-01-at-1.50.37-PM.png 1600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2021/10/Screenshot-2021-10-01-at-1.50.37-PM.png 2098w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can now contribute to Chatwoot and participate in Hacktoberfest. Please see the guidelines below. Feel free to reach out to us if you need any help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-contributions&quot;&gt;Code contributions&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Look for the issues tagged with &quot;hacktoberfest&quot; to implement features or fix bugs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ask the team to assign the ticket to you if you are willing to pick it up.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add test cases on RSpec/Jest/Cypress.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;documentation&quot;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you find something missing in the documentation? Contribute to our docs by raising a pull request at our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/docs&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;translation&quot;&gt;Translation&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are huge proponents of making software available in native languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We support 30+ languages right now. We expect this to grow to 50+ languages by March 2022.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://translate.chatwoot.com&quot;&gt;https://translate.chatwoot.com&lt;/a&gt; or Github repository for contributing translations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If none of the above items suits your interest, you can try using the product and start reporting bugs or feedback.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are very excited to see your contributions. Happy #Hacktoberfest.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chatwoot - August Update]]></title><description><![CDATA[We are starting a new series from this month, where we would share exciting things happening around Chatwoot. We will share the product updates, progress, community events, etc., through these...]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/chatwoot-august-update</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/chatwoot-august-update</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 11:17:36 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We are starting a new series from this month, where we would share exciting things happening around Chatwoot. We will share the product updates, progress, community events, etc., through these.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;funding-announcement&quot;&gt;Funding announcement&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We went through the YC W21 batch during Jan-March 2021. Post YC batch, we raised $1.6M in a seed funding round from Goat Capital, Uncorrelated Ventures, YCombinator, and a host of angel investors, including Lambda School CEO Austen Allred. This funding round would help us improve the product and release a scale version of Chatwoot with more features. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the round &lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2021/08/09/chatwoot-challenges-zendesk-with-open-source-customer-engagement-platform/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;10000-github-stars&quot;&gt;10,000 Github stars&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The community has been core to us. It is inspiring to see that we continue to get love and support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-08-30-at-6.53.18-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;1122&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-08-30-at-6.53.18-PM.png 600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-08-30-at-6.53.18-PM.png 1000w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-08-30-at-6.53.18-PM.png 1122w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crossing 10,000 stars on Github is a huge milestone for us. We are delighted to build this community of people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-million-docker-downloads&quot;&gt;1 Million Docker downloads&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-02-at-4.29.43-PM.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;1434&quot; height=&quot;438&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-02-at-4.29.43-PM.png 600w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-02-at-4.29.43-PM.png 1000w, https://www-internal-blog.chatwoot.com/content/images/2021/09/Screenshot-2021-09-02-at-4.29.43-PM.png 1434w&quot; sizes=&quot;(min-width: 720px) 720px&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Docker has been one of our most used installation mediums, and it continues to do so. Our official Docker images crossed 1 Million downloads last month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;product-update&quot;&gt;Product Update&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We released a new version of Chatwoot v1.19.0 with a lot features, including custom push notification servers, snooze a conversation, campaigns, etc. You can read more about the release &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/v1-19-0/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-started&quot;&gt;Get started&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Start using Chatwoot on Cloud: &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.chatwoot.com&quot;&gt;https://app.chatwoot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Spin up a Self-hosted instance: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chatwoot.com/docs/self-hosted&quot;&gt;https://www.chatwoot.com/docs/self-hosted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make sure to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/chatwoot&quot;&gt;star us on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Follow us &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chatwootapp&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/chatwoot&quot;&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Become a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sponsors/chatwoot&quot;&gt;sponsor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Implementing Deep linking in  React native mobile apps]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learnings from implementing Deep linking in Chatwoot mobile apps
We live in a world where things are interlinked. We share links more frequently than ever before and want our customers to reach their desired pages...]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/implementing-deep-linking-in-react-native</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/implementing-deep-linking-in-react-native</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 06:22:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learnings from implementing Deep linking in Chatwoot mobile apps&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We live in a world where things are interlinked. We share links more frequently than ever before and want our customers to reach their desired pages swiftly, regardless of their platforms. Deep links could help significantly in enhancing this experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-deep-linking&quot;&gt;What is deep linking?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep linking enables a user to navigate to specific content in a mobile application using a URL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep links are web links that can activate your app and contain information needed to load specific app sections. They can be used as triggers in external events like &lt;em&gt;push notification, emails, web links etc.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They enable users to save more time and energy without locating a particular page by themselves – significantly improving the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: The &quot;deep&quot; refers to the depth of the page in a hierarchical app structure of pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-deep-linking&quot;&gt;Why deep linking?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deeplinking enhances the user experience for mobile app users. Before implementing Deep linking In Chatwoot, a user on a mobile device clicking on a conversation link received via an email would be taken to the web browser, even if they have the Chatwoot app installed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With deep linking, the Chatwoot app can open the conversation screen based on the id in the URL. Then, when the user clicks on a link, it will open the app, and the user is navigated to the exact point in the app where they are destined. This is a much better user experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chatwoot.com/c672ada90e37eecfd0ae0beaff4f976d/deeplinking-demo.gif&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;deep-linking-demo&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-implement-deep-linking&quot;&gt;How to implement Deep Linking?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deep links can be implemented in ios and android by the following methods :&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Custom URL scheme (iOS Universal Links)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Intent URL (Android)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;configuration-for-android&quot;&gt;Configuration for Android&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add an &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/intents-filters&quot;&gt;intent-filter&lt;/a&gt; in AndroidManifest.xml to specify the host link&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;data android:scheme=&quot;https&quot; android:host=&quot;http://app.chatwoot.com/&quot; /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then build the project. To test this action, run the following command in your terminal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;adb shell am start -W -a android.intent.action.VIEW -d &quot;https://app.chatwoot.com/app/accounts/1/conversations/12121&quot; com.chatwoot.app
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now the app will open up successfully if everything went well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;configuration-for-ios&quot;&gt;Configuration for iOS&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple recommends Universal links as the way to open your web links in your mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To support universal linking in iOS, we need to add some configuration on the server-side as well. First, the endpoint must use HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your server has to have a route that is defined as a get request with the path &lt;strong&gt;/apple-app-site-association.&lt;/strong&gt;. When a request is made to that path, you must return a file with the configuration recommended below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &quot;applinks&quot;: {
        &quot;apps&quot;: [],
        &quot;details&quot;: [
            {
                &quot;appID&quot;: &quot;&amp;lt;TeamID&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;Bundle-Identifier&amp;gt;&quot;,
                &quot;paths&quot;: [ &quot;NOT /super_admin/*&quot;, &quot;*&quot; ]
            }
        ]
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;implementation-on-the-server-side&quot;&gt;Implementation on the server-side&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apart from the configurations required in your mobile app, you would also need to implement some changes on your server for deep links to work for ios.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is an example implementation for a ruby on rails server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;routes.rb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot;&gt;get &apos;apple-app-site-association&apos; =&amp;gt; &apos;apple_app#site_association&apos;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;app/controllers/apple_controller.rb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot;&gt;class AppleController &amp;lt; ApplicationController
  def site_association
    site_association_json = render_to_string action: &apos;site_association&apos;, layout: false
    send_data site_association_json, filename: &apos;apple-app-site-association&apos;, type: &apos;application/json&apos;
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;app/views/apple&lt;em&gt;app/site&lt;/em&gt;association.html.erb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot;&gt;{
    &quot;applinks&quot;: {
        &quot;apps&quot;: [],
        &quot;details&quot;: [
            {
                &quot;appID&quot;: &quot;&amp;lt;%= ENV[&apos;IOS_APP_ID&apos;] %&amp;gt;&quot;,
                &quot;paths&quot;: [ &quot;NOT /super_admin/*&quot;, &quot;*&quot; ]
            }
        ]
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find the implementation of Universal links in Chatwoot in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/chatwoot/pull/805&quot;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once your server endpoint is ready, Launch Xcode. Select the Signing &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;Capabilities&lt;/strong&gt; tab and then select the enable &lt;strong&gt;Associated Domains&lt;/strong&gt; and add domains. Make sure to prefix the domain with &lt;code&gt;applinks:&lt;/code&gt; in place of &lt;code&gt;https://&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chatwoot.com/static/b85130d2d4fa3ed12bf6372cf618f580/16abd/deeplinking-xcode.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;deeplinking-xcode&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; title=&quot;deeplinking-xcode&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find the implementation of Universal links in Chatwoot mobile app in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/chatwoot-mobile-app/pull/297&quot;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-steps&quot;&gt;Final Steps&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once our app is ready to handle deep Links, we need to implement actions to navigate the user to required screens. React native has &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactnative.dev/docs/linking&quot;&gt;Linking&lt;/a&gt; module, which will provide API that allows us to listen for an incoming linked url.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linking gives you a general interface to interact with incoming app links. For example, if an app link triggered the app launch, it provides the link url. Otherwise, it will provide null. If we get the link url, it redirects to the exact screen based on the incoming URL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;useEffect(() =&amp;gt; {
 // Get the deep link used to open the app
   const initialUrl = await Linking.getInitialURL();
 // Redirect to particualr screen based on inital url
   navigation.navigate(&apos;ChatScreen&apos;);
}, []);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your mobile app should now be ready to handle deep links if you have followed the above instructions. Thank you for reading, and I hope you liked it. Please let us know if you have any doubts ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[External service callbacks made easy with LocalTunnel]]></title><description><![CDATA[Improve development experience with external service callbacks from Facebook, Twitter, Twilio etc., using LocalTunnel. Working with third-party integrations As a product developer, one of the biggest pain points that you come across might be related to working with…]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/manage-external-service-callbacks-with-local-tunnel</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/manage-external-service-callbacks-with-local-tunnel</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 06:20:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Improve development experience with external service callbacks from Facebook, Twitter, Twilio etc., using LocalTunnel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-with-third-party-integrations&quot;&gt;Working with third-party integrations&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a product developer, one of the biggest pain points that you come across might be related to working with callbacks (mostly webhooks) from third party systems in your local development environment. Most of us use some tunnelling software to expose our local server to the internet and then use that URL for the callbacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some pain points with this setup. Usually, tunnelling software has this annoying side-effect of changing the exposed URL every time you restart. If you have shared it with your colleagues for testing, you would have to send the new URL again. If you are working on the webhook callbacks with third-party integrations, like Facebook, Twitter, Zapier, Twilio, etc., this becomes frustrating. Every time you restart the tunnel, you have to go to the developer console and update the callback URL. This workflow is cumbersome, and often we forget this and spend a good amount of time debugging on other things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;chatwoots-context&quot;&gt;Chatwoot&apos;s Context&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Chatwoot, we have multi-channel support and have inbox support for Facebook, Twitter, Twilio, Slack, chatbots, and various email platforms. We constantly struggled with this problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One way to mitigate the problem was by getting individual paid accounts for every team member and get a static URL for the tunnel. This approach solved some of the issues as we don&apos;t need to update the callback URLs every time we restart the local system. For the entire period of development, the URL stays the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything seemed good initially. After some time, we started running into problems again with this setup. When multiple engineers work on a single integration, they have to change the callback URL to their tunnel URL whenever they work on it. Nobody called dibs on this, and often we forget to check the callback URL when we start the work. We were on the path to expand our integrations as a part of the omnichannel support and we wanted a better development experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We needed the API callback URLs to stay constant, and it should be easy for any developer to get hold of that tunnel URL. As a possible solution, we looked for open source tunnelling softwares that we could host and customize. That is when we came across LocalTunnel and fell in love with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-localtunnel&quot;&gt;What is LocalTunnel?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;LocalTunnel exposes your localhost to the world for easy testing and sharing. It is an open-source software. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/localtunnel/localtunnel&quot;&gt;https://github.com/localtunnel/localtunnel&lt;/a&gt;). From the number of stars and forks of this project, you can see that the community loves this product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-we-set-it-up&quot;&gt;How did we set it up?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We decided to set up our own LocalTunnel on a Digital Ocean droplet. We followed &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/quark-works/running-your-own-reverse-proxy-with-localtunnel-b1658e239c35&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; excellent article written by Alex to host LocalTunnel on Digital Ocean. In addition to the setup guide, we had to open a range of ports on the droplet to allow TCP connections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We pointed one of the subdomains to the droplet that runs LocalTunnel, which looks something like &lt;code&gt;https://tunnel.example.com&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;development-workflow&quot;&gt;Development Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To start working with LocalTunnel, you have to install the LocalTunnel client on your machine using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;npm install -g localtunnel
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can connect to the LocalTunnel server by specifying the port and a host name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;lt --port 3000 --host http://tunnel.example.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;By default, LocalTunnel would generate a subdomain using random characters. The URL would look like &lt;code&gt;https://[random-characters].tunnel.example.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, LocalTunnel allows you to request a named subdomain on the LocalTunnel server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;lt --port 3000 --host http://tunnel.example.com --subdomain customsubdomain
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This feature allowed us to standardize the list of subdomains to the external services as seen below:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-begin: html--&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Service&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Subdomain&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Facebook&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;fb-dev.tunnel.example.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sendgrid&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;sendgrid-dev.tunnel.example.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mailgun&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;mailgun-staging.tunnel.example.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Twitter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;twitter-staging.tunnel.example.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Twilio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;twilio-dev.tunnel.example.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;!--kg-card-end: html--&gt;&lt;p&gt;An important thing to note here is that when we use a subdomain, for example, Facebook development as &lt;code&gt;fb-dev.tunnel.example.com&lt;/code&gt;, we set all the callbacks on the Facebook developer account to this subdomain. Similarly, we set the callback URL on the Twitter developer account for Twitter app development to &lt;code&gt;twitter-dev.tunnel.example.com&lt;/code&gt; and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For working on Facebook inbox, we would connect to the standard tunnel URL:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;lt --host http://tunnel.example.com --subdomain fb-dev --port 3000
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this approach, we solved both problems mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Now that you had a standard set of URLs, you don&apos;t have to go to the developer console every time to change it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Any team member can get hold of any of these tunnels using their LocalTunnel Client seamlessly.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This approach has improved our development workflow to a great extend. The developers don&apos;t have to worry about the URL they would use in development. If they conform to the standard URL, everything works seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let us know if you have any questions or if this article helped you in improving your development experience. We are all ears. :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Woot Journals: 2020 - The year in review]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog about the progress we made in 2020. 2020 was an overwhelming year for everyone globally due to a global pandemic, concerns over political unrest and racial injustice, climate change etc…]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/2020-year-in-review</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/2020-year-in-review</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 06:18:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A blog about the progress we made in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2020 was an overwhelming year for everyone globally due to a global pandemic, concerns over political unrest and racial injustice, climate change etc. Amidst all that, we have seen many heroic responses that gave us hope and helped us think positively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Chatwoot, we have seen a surge in interest in the usage from developers and a wide variety of companies. Let us take a look back at what have done so far and what we think about the future of Chatwoot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-project&quot;&gt;The project&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/chatwoot&quot;&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt; has seen tremendous growth in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stars went from ~2k to ~6.7k.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The number of contributors has grown from &lt;strong&gt;~30&lt;/strong&gt; in Jan to &lt;strong&gt;100+&lt;/strong&gt; in December.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Our application supports more than 25 different regional languages.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We had more than 600 commits in the project last year.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We released our mobile application on &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/ug/app/chatwoot/id1495796682&quot;&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.chatwoot.app&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=US&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/muhsin-k&quot;&gt;Muhsin&lt;/a&gt;, who took the complete ownership of the app and showed an extraordinary work.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-product&quot;&gt;The product&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year, we were supporting only two customer conversation channels. Now we support seven different customer conversation channels including Website Live Chat, Facebook, Twitter, WhatsApp, SMS, Email and an API channel allowing developers to build custom workflows on top of Chatwoot. We now have a mini CRM which will enable you to see the profile of the people you are talking to and delight them with contextual support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had releases every month. Here is a small recap on what we have released so far.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-embed-card&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe scrolling=&quot;no&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cPwhnp9S1Bs?autoplay=0&amp;amp;fs=0&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=3&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;cc_load_policy=0&amp;amp;start=0&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;origin=https://youtubeembedcode.com&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is how the design of widget evolved over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chatwoot.com/static/c281c15499e37ecdeee280adf8993ac6/16abd/chatwoot_widget_design.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;chatwoot_widget_design&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; title=&quot;chatwoot_widget_design&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-team-remote-work&quot;&gt;The team &amp;amp; remote work&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many countries were under complete lockdown for months, and it was necessary to figure out an alternate path for business continuance. Remote work became a necessity rather than a nice to have. We saw large companies announcing fully remote work, accelerators running cohorts remotely, newsroom running from their news reader&apos;s house providing flexibility and freedom to the people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a glad thing that our team embraced the concept of working remotely even before pandemic hit us. Our team has been working with various industry leaders remotely for more than three years. Moving on to completely remote work was not a new thing for us. Our team has not met in the last seven months due to travel restrictions in place. Still, we were able to get good progress in the product and the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The future&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With previous experience in the customer experience industry, our team has been talking to many people to understand what Chatwoot can do better to make their life easier. Here are a couple of observations we had:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Concerns:&lt;/strong&gt; With the introduction of data privacy regulations like GDPR &amp;amp; CCPA, the companies are concerned about sharing their customer data with third-party solutions. The need for self-hosted tools is on the rise.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple tools, fragmented data:&lt;/strong&gt; A surprising aspect we found during our interviews about the tools companies is that they all use more than one tool to interact with their customers. Most companies have a live chat tool, an email campaign tool, a social media tool etc. The customer data is fragmented.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unexpected price hikes:&lt;/strong&gt; There is no control over the companies&apos; pricing of third-party tools. If it is related to their customer data, it is tough for them to migrate to other software.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Chatwoot, we can solve this problem by placing ourselves as a self-hosted customer data hub allowing companies to hang out without their customers from one place. We have a long way to go. With the team working full time on Chatwoot and the features planned for the next releases, the future of Chatwoot looks bright and exciting. We have a couple more exciting news to share with you. We will do that in the next couple of posts. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Woot Journals: How to decide pricing plans for an open-source product?]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog about how Chatwoot pricing has evolved over time
TLDR: Start selling services, identify the value you provide and decide pricing plans based on it.
In this blog post, let me describe how we make our pricing...]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/how-to-decide-pricing-plans-for-your-opensource-product</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/how-to-decide-pricing-plans-for-your-opensource-product</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 06:17:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A blog about how Chatwoot pricing has evolved over time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;TLDR: Start selling services, identify the value you provide and decide pricing plans based on it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, let me describe how we make our pricing decisions at Chatwoot. This post should be more relatable for open-source products, rather than opensource libraries or frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the people whom I talked to described to me a &lt;strong&gt;value-based pricing framework&lt;/strong&gt; which didn&apos;t make much sense to us, at that time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, SaaS businesses need to identify the value it provides to the user and price it correctly. But, how do you know what features or services are helpful, and how it improves the customer&apos;s businesses during your early stages?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don&apos;t! There is not enough information about how people are using your product and what they like about it. Alternatively, you can take a look at the competitors and see how their pricing plan works. This decision becomes even more complicated when you have an opensource product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-chatwoot-pricing-story&quot;&gt;The Chatwoot pricing story&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we started Chatwoot, We had two types of paid offerings in mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chatwoot Cloud:&lt;/strong&gt; A SaaS version where customers would pay for the features Chatwoot provides.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-premise Plans:&lt;/strong&gt; Support plans for On-Premise Chatwoot installations, which gives the users more flexibility and control over the data.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seeing the introduction of data privacy regulations like GDPR and CCPA, we started with on-premise plans initially. We decided to adopt an effort based pricing model. We were not charging for the features, but were charging for the support we offer. It was a comfortable option to start with. So we started selling the support plans for installation and upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We estimated a 30-60 minutes worth of manual effort every month for a client with the automation we had in place. We started with a base plan of $20 per month. It was an experiment to see whether people were willing to pay us, and it did work. People started buying our support plans. Later, we figured the effort put vs margin we get is pretty slim, so we updated the pricing plan to $49 per month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Soon, people started asking for customizations, custom integrations, branding etc. We introduced a new plan with $299 per month, which would provide additional customizations and priority features requests. This offering worked for a couple of customers. Later, when we looked at the effort we put into these custom installations vs the value people were receiving, the margin seemed unbalanced. It made us reevaluate our pricing plans. We reworked our pricing plans to introduce three different plans at $299, $499 and $999+ per month, which is what we have in place now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-learned&quot;&gt;What we learned ?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All these times, we have never asked our existing customers to pay more. They continue to be in the same plan they signed up. The revisions applied to new customers only.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This approach has given us enough time and space to understand what people like and what they don&apos;t. It also gave us insights on how people use our product. There is less churn compared to conventional SaaS business where people close the account the moment they start experiencing problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As more companies are planning open-source as their GTM strategy and the market starting to become more aware of on-premise support services, it has become relatively easier to sell these support plans. To price a product, you need to identify the value you provide. And to get there, you need customer adoption with a feedback loop. A support based pricing model fits well for this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are still learning new lessons and fine-tuning these pricing models. And we will continue sharing as we chug along 😃.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Woot Journals:  One year since open-sourcing Chatwoot]]></title><description><![CDATA[Looking into the one year of open-sourcing Chatwoot. Chatwoot is now one of the most popular open-source live chat software on Github. If you haven’t been following the story so far, here is the story…]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/woot-journals-one-year-since-open-sourcing-chatwoot</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/woot-journals-one-year-since-open-sourcing-chatwoot</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 06:15:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking into the one year of open-sourcing Chatwoot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chatwoot is now one of the most popular open-source live chat software on Github. If you haven’t been following the story so far, here is the story, in a nutshell, to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chatwoot started as a commercial project in 2016 and strived to help businesses provide exceptional customer support through Facebook messenger. The product inspiration came through the customer pain points which we observed while working in this space as a part of our previous gigs. Nevertheless, the project didn&apos;t culminate into a viable business and we shut shop in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the amount of sweat we put into the project, Chatwoot still stayed alive in our hearts. In 2019, as an impromptu decision, we ended up open-sourcing the project as a part of the #hacktoberfest. The story took a different twist then and Chatwoot went on to be a top post on Hackernews. Ever since then, the project has been growing at an incredible pace with almost 5k stars on Github currently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today marks a year since the initial commit for Chatwoot’s resurrection as an open-source project and so let&apos;s take a step back to look at Chatwoot&apos;s journey in the last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-decision-to-go-open-source&quot;&gt;The Decision to go open-source&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;How do you start a popular open-source project?&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, we might have told our story countless times. However, often, the larger story fails to capture the minute moments and the thought processes behind deciding to go open-source. Many a time, we have felt that the Chatwoot story as an answer to the question &lt;code&gt;How did you decide to go open-source?&lt;/code&gt;  leaves the questioner unsatisfied. That said, in all honesty, there was never a grand scheme behind the decision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the second quarter of 2019, the core Chatwoot team was back together prototyping yet another SaaS product. It was in one of our regular sync-up calls that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pranavrajs&quot;&gt;@pranavrajs&lt;/a&gt; floated the idea of making Chatwoot open-source. The idea didn’t attract any criticism, but there wasn’t too much enthusiasm in the air either, thanks to our Imposter Syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our experience in open-source till that point was limited to being consumers. Being ardent fans of the code quality in open source projects like Vue.js and ruby on rails, we had our insecurities exposing the project to the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With zilch expectations, we went through it like just another day in our lives and decided to commit the codebase to GitHub. We would leave it there while the team continued working on our next big thing, we had thought! ;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;ignition-ready-set-go&quot;&gt;Ignition: Ready Set Go&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In August 2019, as unprepared as we were, Chatwoot codebase was brought out as a public repo. Our expectation of an uneventful day, quickly turned around, thanks to the spammers who got hold of an SES key from an old commit. The incident ended in raking up quite a surprise in the form of AWS billing alerts. We did act swiftly to mitigate the issue, but as far as the business plan behind open source goes, This is the story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;October saw the repo getting some attention thanks to #hacktoberfest, which re-kindled the whole team&apos;s interest in Chatwoot. It even resulted in the team deciding to put on-hold the then on-going project and give Chatwoot our full attention for the next 2 months. We did the much-needed maintenance chores over the repo and ended up shipping the website live chat feature that we lacked in. The absence of other communication channels, especially website live chat, was one of our prime hypotheses behind the earlier failure of Chatwoot. Having been able to ship that feature in 2 weeks, amidst the newfound enthusiasm, is something the team is still extremely proud of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ultimate unexpected kickstart, however, came in December in the form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21559197&quot;&gt;Hackernews&lt;/a&gt;, which we attribute as the start of Chatwoot as a serious open-source business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After Hacktoberfest, we saw the attention on our GitHub repo reducing despite the team shipping new updates. In all helplessness,  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pranavrajs&quot;&gt;@pranavrajs&lt;/a&gt; gave it a final go on ShowHN one night and to our joy, we were received with much love from the community, a wonderful surprise for the whole team, and a sleepless night for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pranavrajs&quot;&gt;@pranavrajs&lt;/a&gt;, replying to comments. Chatwoot hasn’t stopped growing ever since.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;almost-a-year-later&quot;&gt;Almost a year later&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;The work that the Chatwoot community does, matters!&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the adversities since the beginning of 2020, the Chatwoot community continues to generate moments that have carried us through these tough times. Working in isolation from a remote corner of the world, you might fail to see the impact you are creating, but testimonies like the following make us realize why we matter as a community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;I’m so glad I found your software. It’s a tremendous help for startups like me who, because of the global pandemic, had to shift from a physical store to online selling through social media. You guys will save my store as well as the jobs of my employees as we are now about to be efficient in addressing our customers’ inquiries. Again, I’m grateful. &quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are what we are today, not just because of the core team but also because of our 70+ contributors to the codebase, the community members who have been helping us ship in multiple languages and businesses that have opted to go with Chatwoot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last 6 months, Chatwoot has outgrown itself from being a Facebook only chat-solution. We have also seen the community leveraging Chatwoot as a messaging platform for their conversational business need. From specific sectors like healthcare, banking, etc for their data privacy requirements to bot companies looking for a conversational frontend, we continue to see endlessly expanding use cases than we ever imagined for Chatwoot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the flexibility of opensource, we continue to see the community tweak Chatwoot into even powerful solutions. We have been receiving some wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://satchel.com/live-chat/&quot;&gt;reviews&lt;/a&gt; for our cloud version too as we continue to learn from all the comments from the community and work on our future versions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We might have been relatively quiet on our blog for the last couple of months. If it ever seems like we&apos;ve slowed down a bit, you can rest assured that it&apos;s only because our team is working hard on some exciting features. As always, stay tuned for all the cool updates coming your way, real soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[It's a bot story]]></title><description><![CDATA[Building conversational bots into Chatwoot. It’s a bot story Since the initial development days of Chatwoot, we have constantly asked ourselves how the platform should handle chatbots. Right…]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/its-a-bot-story</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/its-a-bot-story</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 06:14:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Building conversational bots into Chatwoot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;it%E2%80%99s-a-bot-story&quot;&gt;It’s a bot story&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the initial development days of Chatwoot, we have constantly asked ourselves how the platform should handle chatbots. Right from building a complete end to end solution for chatbots to just leaving it entirely open to the developers, with Chatwoot being the API platform alone, we have thought through numerous ideas over this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amid this, after open sourcing the project, we also saw the same question being increasingly posted to us by the community as well. To enter a space of clarity here, over the easter weekend, we decided to discuss the idea of chatbots in our product all-hands meeting. Here&apos;s what came out of it -&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-vision&quot;&gt;Our vision&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have always believed in chatbots being crucial in customer support - our faith only reinforced by a lot of companies releasing metrics about how bots reduced more than 30% of their customer enqueries with out the need for an agent intervention. Back in 2017 however, in the early days of Chatwoot, most of the bots available were very dumb. The state of the art implementations then relied on state machines and on an NLP platform like wit.ai. Nobody had it really figured out on how to go about chatbots. While the bots were wonderful for the 30% of time when it worked, when it didn’t, they proved to be nothing less than a nightmare for customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our thoughts on the solution we wanted to build back then was a customer support platform where bots and agents could work together seamlessly. Essentially, instead of bots vs agents, both units co-existing peacefully and working in tandem to solve a query. Consequently, in the year 2017, since we didn’t have enough engineering capacity, we went ahead to built the agent platform, where most of our expertise lay. The idea was to bring in the bot platform later, which happened to not kickstart at that time. We believed back then that the world was still years away from having that one super AI the could solve it all and looking back at it now, the vision still seems to holds true.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;bots-in-chatwoot&quot;&gt;Bots in Chatwoot&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/iedeIMj.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compared to 2016, chatbots have evolved tremendously from being conditionally scripted to ones that can retain context and sentiments across a whole conversation. We also have multiple closed source and open source tools with the likes of dialogueflow, microsoft bot framework, rasa etc available at our disposition to build them. Although the super smart customer support bot still seems to be a far away dream, most customer support platforms in the market like intercom, freshchat and drift, to name a few, offer some form of chatbot implementation in their suite. Along the same lines, in the pursuit of building a complete customer support solution, our team as well is working towards having similar bot capabilities built into Chatwoot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Staying true to our product philosophy, our aim, as always, is to give our users utmost freedom in terms of their choice of options when it comes to bots. As opposed to trying to launch this as a mammoth feature, we will be addressing this in smaller iterations over our next few releases and will be listening to all your feedback. Besides that, we are also eager to have vendors developing their own solutions on top of Chatwoot. Idealy, we would love Chatwoot to remain as the best option for the next chatbot start up, over which they are able build a solution with out having to worry about developing a chat interface or conversation management capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With that, as our first iteration over chatbots, Chatwoot 1.3.0 was released earlier this month constituting,  &lt;code&gt;Agent Bot APIs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;agent-bot-apis&quot;&gt;Agent Bot APIs?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Agent Bot APIs will let you easily integrate any Bot platform into Chatwoot.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agent Bots, in essence, are virtual agents that you could add to your Chatwoot inbox along with your support agents. In any agent bot connected inbox, the bot will first receive the message from the customer before it appears to the agents in their inbox. The bot decides whether it has the confidence to continue the conversation and tries to resolve it. In case it can’t, it then routes the conversation back to an agent and continues to provide assistance to agents while they try to resolve the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;1.3.0&lt;/code&gt; release supplies necessary APIs for the above functionality to work, over which developers can have their solutions. This is particularly focused at vendors and enthusiasts who don’t mind getting their hands dirty. We also hope to get the agent bots platform turn into a marketplace where developers can build custom bot implementations quickly. In our upcoming releases, we look to continue our work over Agent Bots with further integrations and UI options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;implementing-an-agent-bot-in-chatwoot-with-rasa&quot;&gt;Implementing an Agent Bot in Chatwoot with Rasa&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among all the solutions we have explored for building conversational AI into Chatwoot, the one that stands at the top of our list is Rasa. We have been closely following them since their inception, also since their story is extremely relatable to us. Furthermore, being a compteley open source solution, they would be our top recommendation, if you are to ever build a chatbot of your own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Soon after the release of agent bot API’s, our team tried to hack together an integration with rasa platform. Here&apos;s a screen cast to run you through the process-&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-embed-card&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KE4nKgepO_k&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;512px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can explore the demo project by following this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Chatwoot/rasa-agent-bot-demo&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. We hope to see the exciting ideas you will come up by building on top of the Chatwoot &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.Chatwoot.com/developers/api/#tag/AgentBot&quot;&gt;agent bot apis&lt;/a&gt;. As always, do keep sharing your feedback and suggestions as we continue building our chatbot story 🤖.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A new decade and the road ahead]]></title><description><![CDATA[Welcoming a new decade with some exciting news from Chatwoot. It’s 2020 and the decade has begun with the world around us in turmoil. With rising political uncertainties across the globe and a warming planet that…]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/new-decade-and-the-road-ahead</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/new-decade-and-the-road-ahead</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 06:11:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcoming a new decade with some exciting news from Chatwoot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s 2020 and the decade has begun with the world around us in turmoil. With rising political uncertainties across the globe and a warming planet that’s presenting us with new challenges, we all need to buckle up. However, the way communities have come together in these difficult times serve as the much-needed reassurance that it’s surely not the end of the road and that not all hope is lost.  We will persist and thrive together as a community, like always.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With half of our team traveling through south-east Asia right in the midst of the Corona outbreak,  this post has been in draft for way longer than it should have been. Nevertheless, now everyone’s back home, settled and are happy to share with the community some exciting news in the midst of this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;premium-support-plans&quot;&gt;Premium support plans&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever since the start of the journey, we have been asking ourselves the question of whether we should focus more on a hosted solution or on making our self-hosted solution more accessible. On the hosted front, there are a ton of products out there that offer similar functionality and features like Intercom, Freshchat, Zendesk Chat etc. In contrast to these players, we stand tall by being open source and providing users the flexibility to have on-premise installations, with 100% data in your control. Drawing from this, to focus more on making the setup of self-hosted Chatwoot easier,  we are introducing two premium support options:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;The support plus plan is targeted at SMBs who want to use Chatwoot for their support ( available at an Early bird pricing : $20/month). The installation of Chatwoot on your Heroku account will be assisted by our engineers who will also take care of updates whenever a newer version is released, as long as you continue with the plan.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;On the other hand, the enterprise support plan is focused at businesses that would want priority support via email/calls. The base plan starts at 299$/month and pricing is customized based on your requirements.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above being said, all this doesn’t mean that we have stopped working on the hosted version. We are still working out the niggles with our early bird testers before we widely open it to the public. Do shoot us an email at &lt;code&gt;sales@chatwoot.com&lt;/code&gt;, if you don’t mind checking out  bleeding edge software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;chatwoot-goes-mobile&quot;&gt;Chatwoot goes mobile&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Early previews of Chatwoot mobile apps &amp;amp; Mobile SDKs&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ktqPN0j.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Providing support on the go is key for all small business owners. We had this realization right at the start and that’s probably why we had an iOS and Android app for Chatwoot under development all this while. Now, We are pretty close to giving an early preview, so do watch out for our updates in the upcoming weeks. You can also check the progress on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/chatwoot-mobile-app&quot;&gt;git repo&lt;/a&gt;. We are also building out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/android-sdk&quot;&gt;Mobile SDKs&lt;/a&gt; starting with android.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;twitter-integration-twitty-gem&quot;&gt;Twitter Integration &amp;amp; Twitty Gem&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-embed-card&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe scrolling=&quot;no&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; type=&quot;text/html&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RwNzvRvGP8o?autoplay=0&amp;amp;fs=0&amp;amp;iv_load_policy=3&amp;amp;showinfo=1&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;cc_load_policy=0&amp;amp;start=0&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;origin=https://youtubeembedcode.com&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Finally the Twitter channel is available on Chatwoot.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the IndiaOS conference, we received multiple requests to build a Twitter inbox into Chatwoot. Building a Twitter integration has always been in the back of our mind. Since Facebook &amp;amp; Twitter alone constitute the majority of the support tickets received via social media, the integration made perfect sense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the last month, we have actively worked towards releasing this integration. As we worked with Twitter API, looking at the available gems, we felt a lack of support for some of the use cases we wished to solve. This, in turn, has pushed us to release &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/twitty&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Twitty&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, yet another open-source gem to support the Twitter business APIs. More on this will be shared in a separate article that explains our architecture decisions behind Twitty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-january-milestones&quot;&gt;Other January Milestones&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;1.1.0 the best Chatwoot release we ever made 🍎😉&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In January, we shipped a bunch of features in our best ever release, 1.1.0. This includes agent online status in the chat widget, conversation continuity through email, storage support for GCS, Azure, among others. Do try and give us a shout out with your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also made our first appearance in a conference, sharing the Chatwoot story at the IndiaOS event in Bangalore.  We are also looking forward to sharing the story and meeting our community in various forums over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-the-road-ahead&quot;&gt;And The road ahead&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start of this year is pretty exciting as we are starting to see Chatwoot installations being used in production. We also have few partners who are building their product offerings on top of Chatwoot. The product feedback and the bug reports from these users, have been of immense value. We have been working hard to address the bugs identified and incorporate the changes requested into our product pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All this progress did make us think about the direction which we are headed. And we have arrived at a conclusion. Rather than competing over feature comparison pages, we will be sticking to our strengths. Over the course of next few months, the journey will be all about building a minimum viable software offering, which offers strong data privacy attributes and complete control for the people who are using it. As always super thrilled to share this journey with you all.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Red pill or Blue pill? Answering an acquisition offer]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thoughts on the acquisition offer for Chatwoot from a prominent player in Helpdesk SaaS. For those not familiar with the analogy here, the red pill, together with it's opposite, the blue pill, is a popular cultural meme derived from a…]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/answering-an-acquistion-offer</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/answering-an-acquistion-offer</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 06:05:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thoughts on the acquisition offer for Chatwoot from a prominent player in Helpdesk SaaS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those not familiar with the analogy here, the red pill, together with it&apos;s opposite, the blue pill, is a popular cultural meme derived from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zQ1_IbFFbzA&quot;&gt;scene in the 1999 film The Matrix&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a metaphor symbolizing a choice between the “red pill”, representing a life of harsh knowledge and brutal truth of reality contrary to the “blue pill”, a life of luxurious security and tranquil happiness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-backstory&quot;&gt;The Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Saw you guys on HackerNews, how would the word ‘exit’ sound next to your resume?&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks had been pretty busy for us - juggling between managing our inboxes with a ton of exploratory emails from VC firms and receiving user feedback. Amidst all the interesting emails, the one titled &lt;code&gt;“Selling Chatwoot?”&lt;/code&gt;, particularly caught our attention. Besides the candid title, the email, we noticed, had also been sent directly from the inbox of a CEO we admired. Soon enough, we ended up getting on call over the thread.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea for them was straightforward. They wanted to acquire us since Chatwoot is highly complementary to their product offering. They also believed that the acquisition could accelerate the company&apos;s engineering efforts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We put the question out for the whole team to discuss: &lt;code&gt;The red pill or the blue pill?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-choice&quot;&gt;The Choice&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;We want to keep building this for the long term.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We wanted the decision on this to be unanimous. After one whole year of being in the dark and another, spent building this software, guess it would have been easy for the team to go for the glimmer of the limelight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was indeed a happy moment when the whole team was together on the idea that we weren’t going to take the easy exit. The reasoning was simple, we as a team believed, we were still only scratching the surface and didn’t have the slightest idea on where this could go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, we didn’t want to spend the rest of our lives wondering &lt;code&gt;what it could&apos;ve been&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-road-ahead&quot;&gt;The Road Ahead&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;So the red pill all the way. Now what?&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reiterating from the last post, we are striving for continued progress, together with our wonderful community. Over the last few weeks, we have seen interest from projects wanting to build on top of Chatwoot - We have been rooting for the success of these projects, working closely with them. On the other hand, we are also gearing up to release some fresh updates in the upcoming weeks including &lt;code&gt;email collection forms&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mobile apps&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;hosted version&lt;/code&gt;. Exciting times await!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I meditate on the events from the past week, the optimist in me believes that this could well be our “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_Facebook#Sales_negotiations&quot;&gt;facebook’s no to yahoo acquisition offer&lt;/a&gt;” moment while the realist in me can&apos;t help but think if this would become another story that&apos;s forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Either way, ain’t it fun watching it all unfold as we steer through this journey together?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building in the open]]></title><description><![CDATA[The story of a failed startup that turned into a trending open-source project. We released Chatwoot on Hackernews and remained in the top 15 for over a day. A dream start for our small team right? But what happened over the last…]]></description><link>https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/building-in-the-open</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.chatwoot.com/blog/building-in-the-open</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 06:09:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;The story of a failed startup that turned into a trending open-source project.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We released Chatwoot on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21559139&quot;&gt;Hackernews&lt;/a&gt; and remained in the top 15 for over a day. A dream start for our small team right? But what happened over the last few days surely wasn’t an overnight success. Over the coming weeks, we will be sharing our journey so far,  where we are headed and everything in the middle.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-a-nutshell&quot;&gt;In a nutshell&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Chatwoot is a customer support tool for instant messaging channels which can help businesses to provide exceptional customer support.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was Chatwoot’s tagline when we first released it in 2017. At the time, Chatwoot was a Rails application in a private repo, built by 4 friends - all software engineers, with no prior marketing or sales experience. We hacked on the product during our free time, integrated different channels, talked to multiple prospects, but never made a single cent. And, like most startups, Chatwoot failed. We closed shop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward 2019. We decided, instead of letting the code rust in a private repo, why not make the project open source?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision was made during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/&quot;&gt;#hacktoberfest 2019&lt;/a&gt; and we were in for a pleasant surprise. Chatwoot attracted contributions from over 30 countries around the world. It became a trending project on HN, with our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatwoot/chatwoot&quot;&gt;git repo&lt;/a&gt; gaining over 1000+ stars in 2 days and best of all, got a lot of love from the community.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, a failed project is back on track and the prospects are looking great. Our team is back to actively working on the project. We are building it in the open and getting a lot of ideas and contributions from the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;what%E2%80%99s-next&quot;&gt;What’s next&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s still early days for Chatwoot, but what&apos;s transpired over the last couple of weeks has made us feel more responsible towards this project and the community that showed us this love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;We will be pledging more time to Chatwoot. We will be working with the community to build an open alternative to software behemoth who sells overpriced bloated software. While doing this we might fail or succeed, but guaranteed that we will do it together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;And for sure we will have a story to share.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>